# Kenneth Simmons, RN

# DATA ANALYTICS APPRENTICE





https://github.com/latestnight https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenny-simmons/





# **ABOUT ME**

Registered nurse with over six years of experience, transitioning to data analytics with a desire to utilize skills within healthcare. Trained in multiple data analysis technologies. Experience with multiple eHR and eMAR systems, utilization management and bed management.

## SAMPLE DATA PROJECTS

#### **Nashville Food Deserts and Impact on Public Health**

Explored the presence of food deserts in the Nashville area, and the impact that food availability has on public health. Google Places API was utilized to source and map geospatial data. Public health data was obtained by exploring datasets from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, specifically the '500 Cities Project' datasets. Analysis presented using a Tableau Dashboard and PowerPoint presentation.

#### **United Nations GDP and Internet Usage**

Using Python and Jupyter Notebooks, analyzed data sourced from the UN, and examined the relationships between various countries' GDP and the country's internet usage. Illustrated findings using Matplotlib and Seaborn.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Data Analytics Apprentice** 

Nashville Software School 1/2022-4/2022

- Utilizes various Python packages including pandas, GeoPandas, Folium, Seaborn and others to clean and analyze multiple forms of data. Equally comfortable with Excel, including Vlookups, pivot tables and PowerPivot. Experienced with SQL JOINs, CTEs, CASE statements.
- Experienced in presenting data analysis in various forms such as Jupyter Notebooks, and dashboards, including Tableau and Power Bl.

#### Nursing

Vanderbilt University Medical System, Nashville, TN 9/2020-7/2021 Puget Sound Healthcare System, Seattle, WA 6/2019-6/2020 Tennessee Valley Healthcare System, Nashville, TN 9/2015-5/2019

- **Bone Marrow Transplant Nurse**
- **Nurse Officer of the Day**
- **Acting Assistant Nurse Manager**
- Medical/Surgical/Oncology Staff Nurse

#### REFERENCES

Available upon request

# **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School Nashville, TN

- Data Analytics Bootcamp 1/2022-4/2022
- Data Analytics Jumpstart 10/2021

North Seattle College Seattle, WA

> ACEN accredited Associate of Applied Science Degree in Nursing 9/2013-6/2015

## **KEY SKILLS**

- **PYTHON**
- PANDAS/GEOPANDAS
- **SEABORN**
- **FOLIUM**
- JUPYTER NOTEBOOK
- SQL (POSTGRESQL)
- **EXCEL**
- **GIT & GITHUB**
- **TABLEAU**
- **POWER BI**
- **ZOOM & SLACK**
- AGILE METHODOLOGY
- **ELECTRONIC HEALTH RECORDS**